<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>cheminfo ELN documentation Blog</title>
        <link>https://docs.c6h6.org/docs/blog</link>
        <description>cheminfo ELN documentation Blog</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Various improvements]]></title>
            <link>https://docs.c6h6.org/docs/blog/blog-2025-11-12</link>
            <guid>https://docs.c6h6.org/docs/blog/blog-2025-11-12</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Based on user feedback, multiple improvements have been added to the ELN reaction workflow page.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Based on user feedback, multiple improvements have been added to the ELN reaction workflow page.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="copy-reactant-or-product">Copy reactant or product<a href="#copy-reactant-or-product" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Copy reactant or product" title="Direct link to Copy reactant or product">​</a></h2><p>A new icon in the reaction editor allows copying any reactant or product as a molfile V3000.</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Copy reactant and product as molfile" src="/docs/assets/images/copy-as-molfile-433a14c12362cafaf907e661cf55a2f9.gif" width="1178" height="609" class="img_ev3q"></p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="check-stock-location-and-edit-reagents">Check stock location and edit reagents<a href="#check-stock-location-and-edit-reagents" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Check stock location and edit reagents" title="Direct link to Check stock location and edit reagents">​</a></h2><p>When adding reagents to a reaction, the storage location is now displayed for any matching samples in the stock. You can also edit the corresponding sample directly from the reagent list.</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Search stock and edit" src="/docs/assets/images/edit-reagents-9c76750fffbc33a59cbf309559665a75.gif" width="1179" height="612" class="img_ev3q"></p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="set-molfile-and-molecular-formula-from-sample">Set molfile and molecular formula from sample<a href="#set-molfile-and-molecular-formula-from-sample" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Set molfile and molecular formula from sample" title="Direct link to Set molfile and molecular formula from sample">​</a></h2><p>For samples created from imported data (such as NMR spectra), it is now possible to assign both the molecular formula and chemical structure with a single click. You can also open the sample for editing directly.</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Set molfile and MF of sample" src="/docs/assets/images/set-mf-molfile-4df9220e88a03e073b7aea2333c62d92.gif" width="1171" height="615" class="img_ev3q"></p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="define-the-kind-of-product">Define the kind of product<a href="#define-the-kind-of-product" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Define the kind of product" title="Direct link to Define the kind of product">​</a></h2><p>When adding a new product, any reactant or product can now be selected to extract the structure and molecular formula, which is very useful for defining recovered starting material.</p><p>The product of a reaction can now be flagged as the expected product, a side product, or a recovered starting material. Only pure products are considered in yield calculations.</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Edit sample from stock" src="/docs/assets/images/product-kind-103a04fd36f54562c66bdafe423a0966.gif" width="1127" height="651" class="img_ev3q"></p><h1>Edit sample from stock</h1><p>You can now open and edit a sample directly from the stock by double-clicking its entry to access the editing interface.</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Edit sample from stock" src="/docs/assets/images/stock-to-edit-b575b73293777cb8e824f7e3e5750b82.gif" width="1697" height="831" class="img_ev3q"></p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>reactions</category>
            <category>stock</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New editor for reactions]]></title>
            <link>https://docs.c6h6.org/docs/blog/ocl-reaction-editor</link>
            <guid>https://docs.c6h6.org/docs/blog/ocl-reaction-editor</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[The previous JSME editor, which served us for the past 10 years, had several limitations that were challenging to resolve. These included the inability to edit large reactions, difficulties handling enhanced stereochemistry and zero-order bonds, and problems with correctly encoding salts.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The previous JSME editor, which served us for the past 10 years, had several limitations that were challenging to resolve. These included the inability to edit large reactions, difficulties handling enhanced stereochemistry and zero-order bonds, and problems with correctly encoding salts.</p><p>To address these issues, we have now migrated to the new OpenChemLib reaction editor. This editor is designed to overcome all the aforementioned limitations and provide a more robust and flexible editing experience. While we strive to maintain all existing functionalities, some minor differences remain—particularly in the use of keyboard shortcuts. It is highly recommended to familiarize yourself with the shortcuts available in the OpenChemLib <a href="/docs/eln/uuid/ocl-editor">reaction editor</a> to work efficiently.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="adding-structures-from-the-reagents-tables">Adding Structures from the Reagents Tables<a href="#adding-structures-from-the-reagents-tables" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Adding Structures from the Reagents Tables" title="Direct link to Adding Structures from the Reagents Tables">​</a></h2><p>As before, it is possible to enter the structure of commercial products or previously synthesized reagents by clicking on the hexagon icon.</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Adding reactants" src="/docs/assets/images/add-reactants-4db5e0a420838cc670b82bd8e4f43ace.gif" width="1181" height="621" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>Most of the time, the products are structurally close to one of the reagents. To duplicate a reagent, click on the new arrow icon in the toolbar. A popup window will appear, allowing you to select which reagent you would like to duplicate.</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Add product of the reaction" src="/docs/assets/images/product-6f832544717067b9c25d80528c377652.gif" width="1174" height="398" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>Using shortcuts, it is now fast to apply changes and draw the product of the reaction.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="dealing-with-salts">Dealing with Salts<a href="#dealing-with-salts" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Dealing with Salts" title="Direct link to Dealing with Salts">​</a></h2><p>If you create a salt, you can draw the two ions separately. Depending on their relative positions, they will appear either as one or two products. Simply place the ions close to each other so they are combined as a single product.</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Dealing with salts" src="/docs/assets/images/salt-21b286ecffe6a62e72dc17494861c0ca.gif" width="1176" height="398" class="img_ev3q"></p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="zoom-in--out-and-rotate">Zoom In / Out and Rotate<a href="#zoom-in--out-and-rotate" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Zoom In / Out and Rotate" title="Direct link to Zoom In / Out and Rotate">​</a></h2><p>On the canvas, press <kbd>z</kbd> to select the zoom tool (or click the corresponding icon in the toolbar).</p><ul><li>Moving the cursor vertically while pressing will zoom in or out.</li><li>Moving the cursor horizontally while pressing will rotate the selected molecules.</li></ul><p>To select a specific molecule, press <kbd>space</kbd> while your cursor is over the canvas or click the lasso icon. Clicking anywhere else on the canvas will deselect all, and zoom/rotate will apply to the entire canvas. Double-clicking an atom selects the entire molecule, so rotation will apply only to that molecule.</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Add product of the reaction" src="/docs/assets/images/zoom-cdd81eefa1f34070e54cbf5395b9124e.gif" width="1176" height="405" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>Just save the reaction in order to realign the reagents and products.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="enhancing-stereochemistry">Enhancing Stereochemistry<a href="#enhancing-stereochemistry" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Enhancing Stereochemistry" title="Direct link to Enhancing Stereochemistry">​</a></h2><p>In some cases, you may create many stereocenters that have known relationships. For example, the addition of bromine on an olefin creates such relationships.</p><p>The editor allows you to define groups of stereocenters and specify if both configurations apply ('&amp;'), or only one of them. If only one configuration exists, you can specify whether it is known absolutely ('abs') or if it could be either one ('or').</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Dealing with enhanced stereochemistry" src="/docs/assets/images/stereo-bf3c6dac62c2b9bb29814f617a90a2dc.gif" width="1180" height="399" class="img_ev3q"></p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>reactions</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[We migrate our docs to docusaurus]]></title>
            <link>https://docs.c6h6.org/docs/blog/migrating_to_docusaurus</link>
            <guid>https://docs.c6h6.org/docs/blog/migrating_to_docusaurus</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[We will migrate the documentation for the cheminfo ELN to docusaurus. This will allow us to have one global documentation page to which we can link if users have questions and in which users can perform a global fulltext search.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We will migrate the documentation for the cheminfo ELN to docusaurus. This will allow us to have one global documentation page to which we can link if users have questions and in which users can perform a global fulltext search.</p><p>There are a few technical difficulties on the way:</p><ul><li><p><em>Link to the appropriate pages in the views</em>: In the views, the documentation currently uses the <code>uuid</code> of the view to get the appropriate documentation page from our GitBook project.
We would need to replace this mechanism in some way. In the simplest version, it could be a simple link to page of this documentation website.</p></li><li><p><em>Different deployment might want to have some custom pages.</em> A solution to this would be that the administrators make their own fork for this repo. Currently, it is solved via git submodules</p></li><li><p><em>Fix the organization:</em>  In the GitBook project we have a lot of folders and the organization of some pages does not make sense. This needs to be fixed. Possibly, we should rename <code>introduction</code>, remove some subfolders and fix the capitalization.</p></li></ul>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>docusaurus</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>